Wahyu Sasongko Putro

2014

• Lot 1065 No. 50 KG SG Tangkas, 43000, Kajang, Selangor Phone: +6011-3993-0797 • E-Mail: wsphidjo@gmail.com



Profile

Name/Nick name: Wahyu Sasongko Putro/Wahyu (Male) Vision : To be inspiring and helping everyone Day of bird : 10 December 1987 (30 years-2017)

Nationality : Indonesia

Total Experience: 4 Years (3 years research experience, 1 year work experience) Current address: Lot 1065 No. 50 KG SG Tangkas, 43000, Kajang, Selangor Permanent address: Jl. Aryo Bebangah No. 228A, 61254, Sidoarjo, East Java

Phone : +6011-3993-0797

Availability : Immediate

Education

M.Sc. Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia (UKM), Malaysia. M.Sc. Science in Space Science Centre (ANGKASA), Institute Of Climate Change (Ongoing-Waiting graduation).

B.Sc. Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember, Surabaya, Indonesia. B.Sc. Engineering Physics
Diplm. Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember, Surabaya, Indonesia. Diplm. Engineering Physics

Work Experience

• Research Assistant (Full Time), Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia 2014 – June 2016

• Private teacher in physics and mathematics studies 2015

• Software Engineer (Full Time), PT. Data Integra Dinamika, East

Java, Surabaya, Indonesia

2011-2012

Publications

• Suparta, W. and Putro, W.S., 2014. Analysis distribution of galactic cosmic rays particle energy with polar orbit satellite for Geant4 application. In *Journal of Physics: Conference Series* (Vol. 495, No. 1, p. 012038). IOP Publishing.

 Suparta, W. and Putro, W.S., 2014. Modeling of soft sensor based on artificial neural network for galactic cosmic rays application. In Journal of Physics: Conference Series (Vol. 539, No. 1, p. 012021). IOP Publishing.

 Putro, W.S. and Lestari, R.E., 2015. The scoring quality of astronauts' sleeps using Fuzzy C-Means (FCM) during microgravity effect in the International Space Station (ISS). Scientific Journal of PPI-UKM, 2(1), pp.1-3.

• Suparta, W., Putro, W.S., Singh, M.S.J. and Asillam, M.F., 2015, August. The estimation of rainfall and precipitation variation during 2011 convective system using an artificial neural network over Tawau, Sabah. In <i>Space Science and Communication (IconSpace)</i> , 2015 International Conference on (pp. 479-484). IEEE.	2015
 Suparta, W., Putro, W.S., Singh, M.S.J. and Asillam, M.F., 2015. Characterization of GPS and meteorological parameters for mesoscale convective systems modelover Tawau, Malaysia. <i>Advanced Science Letters</i>, 21(2), pp.203-206. 	2015
Conference paper and presentations	
 Presentation: 1st International conference on science and technology applications in climate change (STACLIM), Bali, Indonesia, (Speaker). 	2015
 Presentation: Space Science and Communication (IconSpace), 2015 International Conference IEEE, Langkawi, Malaysia, (Speaker). 	2015
 Presentation: International Conference Multidisciplinary Academic (ICMA), Kuala Lumpur, Malaysia, (Speaker). 	2015
 Workshop: Basic big data processing for beginner, Surabaya, Indonesia, (Speaker). 	2014
 Workshop: Introduction of Object-oriented programming (OOP), Surabaya, Indonesia, (Participant) 	2014
• Workshop: Basic instrumentation and measurement, Surabaya, Indonesia, (Speaker)	2014
Project Experience	
 Developer thunderstorm modeling for weather station in Tawau (MOSTI project Grant SF-1100) Universiti Kebangsaan Malaysia (UKM), Malaysia. 	2013-2016
 Data base developer Tactical Team Trainer (TTT) simulation, PT. Data Integra Dinamika, Surabaya, Indonesia. 	2012
 Design of smart bioreactor and monitoring system using LabView, Institut Sepuluh Nopember Surabaya (ITS), Indonesia. 	2011
 Maintenance electrical system and Diesel genset over Angkasa Pura, Juanda Airport, Surabaya, Indonesia. 	2010
 Design of green house for hidroponics plant and monitoring system, Institut Sepuluh Nopember Surabaya (ITS), Indonesia. 	2009
 Maintenance helper in Heat Recovery Steam Generator-HRSG plan over PT. IPMOMI power plan, Paiton, Situbondo, Indonesia 	2008

Professional membership

•	IEEE member chapter UKM	2015
•	Member of SCOPUS (bibliographic database containing abstracts and	2016
	citations for academic journal articles)	
•	Member of ORCID (Open Researcher and Contributor ID)	2016

Affiliations/Memberships

•	Angkasa Student Association (ASA), Malaysia	2015
•	Indonesian Student Association - UKM (PPI-UKM), Indonesia	2016

Salary (Basic + Benefits + Allowances)

• Current: RM 2000

• Expected Salary: RM 3500~5500 (nego)

Technical, Communication, and writing skill

Skill	Software/Language	Status
Technical	Ms. Office	Expert
	Linux	Good
	iOS	Good
	Windows	Expert
	SQL database	Good
	PHP	Moderate
	HTML	Good
	Python	Good
	Matlab	Expert
	Electrical and Hardware (IT)	Expert
	Minitab	Expert
	Web browser (Firefox, oprera, etc)	Expert
	C++	Good
	Pascal	Moderate
	Bash (Linux and iOS language)	Moderate
	Visual studio	Basic
	Adobe Photoshop	Moderate
	AutoCAD	Basic
	SAP management	Basic
	Video editor	Expert
Communication	Melayu	Expert
	English	Good
	Germany	Basic
Writing	Melayu	Good
	English	Expert
	Germany	Moderate

Future plant, objective, if I'm selected become to employee

- My dedication for company is growing up the income and reached set point due to i have experienced working under team and personal.
- My skills to improve weakneses Company to reached the vision and reputation company, respectively.
- My loyality used to increase the mission company and work quality due to Im self-learner and hardworker.

Interests and additional skills

- IT and Technology: I have familiar and extensive knowledge of Ms. Office, SQL, Pascal, C++, Linux and Java language. I am confident in the use of technology to support my research such as create model, GUI application and Analyze system. In my work role I use MATLAB software to analyze the system and process the data.
- Languages: I am fluent of Bahasa Melayu, Bahasa Indonesia, and English (written and oral). I also learn deutsche sprache (Germany language) in level A1 over 2015.

References

- Assoc. Prof. Dr. Wayan Suparta, Science in Space Science Centre (ANGKASA), Institute Of Climate Change, Email: wayan@ukm.edu.my, Telp: 603-8911 8485, Fax: 603-8911 8490.
- Dr. Gunawan Nugroho, Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember, Surabaya, Indonesia, Engineering Physics, Email: gunawan@ep.its.ac.id. Telp: +62815-5313-2408
- Hendra Cordova, Institut Teknologi Sepuluh Nopember, Surabaya, Indonesia, Engineering Physics, Email: hcordova@ep.its.ac.id.